At the time, I felt something wasn't quite right.
当时我就觉得有点儿不对
Now, thinking back on it,
我现在想想
why did I talk about that girl?
我为什么要聊那个女生呢
As an old hand at this,
我啊作为一名老瘤子
I should have talked about myself.
我应该聊我自己呀
Because I'm all about speed.
因为我是速度啊
To bring glory to our country
为国争光啊
Continuously venturing out
不断的啊向外出击啊
This is a truly excellent example
这是一个非常非常好的一个例子
But my new followers don't know about my glorious past.
但是我的新粉丝并不了解我这些光辉的过去啊
Thinking back 15 years, I was a student in France
想到15年前我是一名在法国的留学生啊
At that time, I posted a bug in my life
当时我发表了一条人生的bug啊
What was this life bug called
这个人生的bug叫什么呢
It was learning French
就是学法语
Learning French can fulfill three things for you
学法语呢能够满足你三件事
One can help you prepare for the postgraduate entrance exam
一个就是能帮你考研
Another can assist you in preparing for the civil service exam
一个是能帮你考公
And it can even help you find a girlfriend I've been mentioning this to everyone from the very beginning From 2007 to 2010 I was in France During this period in France
还能帮你找到女朋友啊 啊这个事情呢我从一开始跟大家说起啊 07年到10年的时候 我一直在法国啊 这段时间呢在法国
French universities have a three-year system
法国的大学是3年制
So if you know French
所以如果你会法语的话
Applying to universities in France
申请法国的大学
Universities in France are free
法国的大学是免费的
While most people in China attend a four-year university
而大部分人在中国念的大学是4年制
This means if you apply for a master’s program
也就是说你去申请研究生
You can directly apply for the second year of the master’s program
只要直接申请研二就行了
So, the real watered-down master’s degree is in France
所以真正的水硕是在法国
Many people say they haven’t even mastered English yet
很多人说我英语还没学明白呢
Why learn French then
为什么要学法语呢
Actually, everyone just needs a high school level of English
其实大家只要有高中的英语水平
I've taken the college entrance exam
参加过高考
French isn't difficult to learn
法语是不难学习的
It's just that the verbs can be tricky
法语只是动词比较难
But they are all Latin-based words
但是都是拉丁文词啊
Many nouns are the same as in English
名词有很多跟英文都是重复的啊
When I was in Paris
我曾经在巴黎的时候
I had a lot of free time
闲的没事儿
I hooked up
我约炮
I hooked up with someone in Montpellier, France
我约到了法国蒙皮里埃哈
Montpellier is a small city between Marseille and Nice. It’s located along the route from Lyon heading south. You’ll find Montpellier as you continue south from Lyon. If you’re traveling from Paris, you should start from Paris Gare de Lyon. I forget whether it’s the North, South, or East station, but it’s likely the South station.
蒙皮里埃是一个在马赛跟尼斯 之间的一个小城市啊 顺着里昂往下走啊 就是蒙皮里埃啊 大家从巴黎坐这个应该是巴黎南站
Paris has several high-speed train stations.
我忘了是北站还是南站还是东站
The journey on the French high-speed train takes about three and a half hours to reach Montpellier.
反正应该是南站啊
I arrived in Montpellier.
到了蒙皮里埃
This place,
这个地方
is a magical experience that I'll never forget in my life.
是让我这辈子难以忘怀的一种神奇的经历啊
The place has a gender ratio
呃这个地方是一个男女比例
that is extremely imbalanced.
极度失调的一座小城
The university town is a bit like Langfang, near Beijing.
大学城就有点像北京之啊周边的这个廊坊一样
Langfang University Town,
廊坊大学城
but this university town is filled with female students.
但这个大学城里边都是女生啊
It’s all the Faculty of Arts.
全都是文学院啊
All sorts of majors that only girls apply for
各种各样的只有女生报的专业啊
At that time, I had a good friend
当时我有一个好朋友
Right
对啊
I went to Montpellier to visit him
那个我去蒙皮里埃找他
What else can young people do, really You know, that kind of thing Isn't that right But that's not the point The point is, I stayed in Montpellier for a few more days It gives me a kind of soul-penetrating horror.
当然年轻人还能干什么事呢 不就干那事吗 对不对啊 但是这个不是重点 重点是我在蒙皮里还待的那几天 给我一种啊穿越灵魂的一种恐怖的感觉
I've never been stared at like this in my life.
就是我这辈子啊没被人这么盯着过
People see Brother Rong at 41 as already being creepy.
就是大家看41岁的荣哥已经是猥琐
Greasy and smelly,
又油又臭啊
with thinning hair,
又这个头发又稀疏
but when I was in my mid-twenties,
但是我二十六七岁的时候
when I was around 24 or 25,
我二十四五岁的时候
I was still quite good-looking.
二十三四岁的时候还是能看的
That was the peak of my life.
那个时候正好是我的那个人生的巅峰
But let's not go out of our way to look for it.
但其实啊咱们也别使劲找吧
I'm actually pretty average-looking.
我长得其实也一般啊
At 05:05, right?
05:05分吧
Not even close to a six.
那六分都算不上
But in Montpellier, it's just incredibly magical.
但是在蒙皮里埃这个地方简直特别神奇
What makes it so magical?
神奇到什么地方
Let me tell you.
我跟你讲
I was with my girlfriend on this tram.
就是我带着我这个女伴在这个电车上
Just like when Big S walks in.
跟大S上这个一走
What's particularly scary is at this moment, girls from various ethnic groups in France from Black to Arab to North African to European all looked at me at once
特别可怕的是什么呢 这个时候法国的各个种族的女生 从黑的到阿拉伯的 到北非的 到欧洲的啊 这个时候齐刷刷的看向我啊
without any sense of embarrassment
就是那种非常不好意思的那种感觉都没有
as if they were about to scrutinize you
就是完完全全就要把你视奸啊
how do you say this
用这个这个是怎么说
Is this called Nanning?
那个这叫南宁不
This is called Nüning.
这个叫女宁啊
Ning is a boy.
宁宁视一个男生
It's like they're about to strip you down.
就是就好像把你衣服扒了
And the next moment, they’re going to pin you to the ground.
下一秒就要把你给摁到地上那种感觉
Then they look at me like wolves eyeing their prey.
然后他们看到我是那种如狼似虎的感觉
But when they see that girl, it’s pure hatred.
但是看到那个女生就是那种极度仇恨
Like they want to tear her apart.
要把它撕碎的那种感觉
You know what I mean?
你知道吗
Because in this place
因为在这个地方
the gender ratio shockingly reaches
男女比例惊人的达到了百分
one to nineteen
这个一比19
a one-to-nineteen ratio is particularly scary
一比19特别可怕
among us, French international students
所以在我们法国留学生当中
many people are hesitant to apply or attend schools here
就有很多人就不敢去或者不敢报这边的学校
because applying to schools here means you likely won't find a boyfriend
因为报这边的学校肯定找不到男朋友
the guys who come here
男生抱到这边来讲
basically end up being the type who run out of steam or end up alone
基本上都是那个什么劲那个什么人亡
Did you know?
你知道吗
But this thing, British students German students and American Canadian students don’t know Later when I studied in Canada Canadians are mostly indifferent Basically, you have to ask three times to get one response So in Canada
但是这个东西呢英国留学生 德国留学生啊 还有美国 加拿大留学生不知道 后来我再到加拿大留学的时候 加拿大人基本上是性冷淡 基本上你约三次才出来一次 所以在加拿大
It was really hard to address my own physiological needs
特别难以解决自己的这个生理需求啊
But at that time, I did look into options in Japan
但是其实那个时候我找过日本的
And also in South Korea
也找过韩国的
But we can delve into that story later
但是后边咱们可以慢慢讲这段故事啊
During this period, I actually interacted with the Japanese
这段时间其实跟日本人
The main issue with the Koreans was the language barrier
跟韩国之间主要是一个语言障碍
Once everyone started speaking English
一旦大家都说英文了
Or everyone started speaking Chinese
或者大家都说中文了啊
The racial barriers were basically gone
这个这个种族障碍就基本上没有了
We're all East Asians
都是东亚人
it's actually quite easy to communicate
其实很好交流啊
if all else fails
实在不行
we can use body language
肢体交流
but let's be honest
但咱们说实在的
in France
在法国
I always recommend everyone
我一直推荐大家
if you're looking for a white person
如果找白人
go for a Hungarian
找匈牙利人
The Finns and the Irish
芬兰人和爱尔兰人啊
are quite friendly towards China
对中国又比较友好
and they are among the white people who are not considered Anglo-Saxon
又是白人里边不算安格鲁萨克逊的人啊
they are considered this kind of fierce people
应该这个算这个凶人啊
or they are considered the Sami people
算那个萨米人
or our ethnic analysis is not so clear
或者算这个咱我们民族分析的不是那么清楚啊
they are considered the Celtic people
这个算这个凯尔特人
they are not of Anglo-Saxon descent
他不是安格鲁萨克逊裔啊
Anglo-Saxon
安格鲁萨克逊
The Germanic people might not have a particularly good impression of you. The Slavic people might be too accurate. Many people suggest looking for someone from Estonia. Or look for someone from Latvia. Or that person from Belarus.
可能日耳曼系的对你那个印象不是特别好 斯拉夫的可能太准 很多人都说找爱沙尼亚的 找这拉脱维亚的 找那个白俄罗斯的啊
The logic goes like this.
这个逻辑是这样
When we talk about it in that context.
就是在那边来讲
Eastern Europeans tend to be larger in build.
东欧人体型比较大
But French people are typically smaller in stature.
但是法国人通常体型比较小
A person from Northern China
一个中国北方人
is actually quite a bit taller than the average French person
其实是比法国人正常的身高要高一头的
and French girls are very open
而且法国女生非常的开放
even among friends
朋友之间也可以
you know
那个啥
if someone asks you to have a cup of coffee
你平时只要有人问你要去喝一杯咖啡吗
it usually means they want to hook up
这个意思就是啪啪啪的意思
many people don't know this
很多人不知道呃
but it's common in Montpellier
但是在蒙皮里埃
Let me tell you about the days I stayed there.
我跟你讲待的那几天
I felt like people were watching me everywhere.
我感觉四处都有人在看
I felt like a piece of raw meat being eyed by others.
我就是我就像一块生肉一样被别人女宁啊
It was an extremely terrifying experience.
这个非常非常可怕的一件事
That's exactly how it was.
就是真的是这样
So I noticed a lot of things.
所以就是我发现很多
Young guys in China,
国内的这个年轻的男大小伙子啊
who fail to get into grad school or pass the entrance exam,
这个毕业考研考不上
you can learn French, you know.
你可以学法语呀
You have to study at least four subjects for the postgraduate entrance exam.
考研你起码要学四门
But for French, you only need to learn one subject. Right? And French universities use an application system. There's no exam. Just a welcome ceremony. And once you complete your master’s in France, you can work in Quebec for a while.
那学法语只要学一门 对不对 而且法国的大学是申请制啊 没有考试 只有欢迎仪式 而且你考完了法国的这研究生 你再去魁北克工作一段时间啊
Then you can move on.
然后你去
Because you know English and French
因为你会了英语跟法语啊
you can navigate Quebec without any barriers
你在魁北克畅通无阻
and you can take the exam to become a civil servant across Canada
而且全加拿大你都可以考加拿大的公务员
with a generous pension
还有丰厚的退休金
and numerous tax exemptions
还有很多的免税政策
working as a civil servant in Canada
而在加拿大当公务员
how prestigious it would be
多么光宗耀祖
how great it is
多么还可以哎
well, how to put it
怎么说呢
This is something many people don't know.
这个很多人不知道啊
Because they have a small circle within their group.
因为他们内部有一个小圈子
We, adhering to the principle of non-interference in internal affairs, will not intervene.
咱们啊本着不干涉他国内政的这个原则
But overall, learning French has many benefits.
但是总之学法语好处多
More people go to France for education.
多去法国上学
Or to Canada to work as civil servants.
去加拿大当公务员
But don't forget the small city called Montpellier.
但是你们不要忘了这个叫蒙皮利叶的小城市
It's in Nice.
在尼斯
On the left side of Cannes.
戛纳的左边
To the right of Marseille
在马赛的右边
To the south of Lyon
在里昂的南边
Remember this street
记住这个街啊
It's called Montpellier
叫蒙皮利叶
Montpellier Also known as Montpellier There are many places like this Only French exchange students know about It's really a very scary place It's been 17 years since I left there.
蒙皮里埃啊 也叫蒙彼啊 反正这个地方很多 只有法国留学生才知道的 真的是非常非常恐怖的一个地方哦 我离开那儿已经有17年了啊
Or maybe 16 years.
17年的16年啊
Fifteen years, to be precise.
15年的时间
But I still remember it vividly.
但是我现在仍然记忆犹新
Rong doesn't exactly have the looks.
荣哥长得真不算是好看啊
But he's got a face that grows on you.
只能说是耐看
When I was 13 or 14, I was the same way.
我20 452十三四的时候也就是耐看
Let's just say 24.
就说24吧
But let's be honest here.
但是咱们说句实在话
There's really a severe shortage of men there.
当地真的是太缺男生了啊
The place really gives off a sense of being overly aggressive.
那个地方真的就是如狼似虎的感觉
People can just strip you down.
就是人能把你扒了
I got groped three times while walking those few days.
我那几天走路被摸屁股就摸了三回
Can you even imagine that?
就是就是你想象的到吗
It's others who are touching your butt.
是别人摸你屁股
French people are really open, you know.
就是法国人是真开放啊
It's just a pure expression of affection.
就是纯粹一种好感的表达
At that point, you don't feel like it's sexual harassment or anything.
这时候你就不觉得是什么性骚扰之类的
It's really scary
真的很可怕
I didn't dare to go out at night
晚上根本都不敢出门
My girlfriend acted like a thief
我那女伴儿就像做贼一样
She just hid me at home
就是把我藏在家里边
That's how it was
就是这样
Those days were extremely exhausting
然后那几天是体力非常透支
Haha, it was really tough But later, I often went on vacation After breaking up with that person I often chose to go to Montpellier Many people don't understand why I would go to this southern town
呵呵真的是不容易 但是后来我数次度假啊 跟那个人分开了以后 数次度假都是愿意去蒙皮利埃 很多人不明白为什么我要去这座南方小城
This is the story of a hidden paradise
这就是桃花源记的故事
Not many people know the beauty of it
并不是很多人并不知道这个其中的美好之处啊
I also suggest you don't go to areas like Amsterdam
也建议大家不要去什么阿姆斯特丹区
To visit the red-light district
去逛红灯区啊
The Dutch are tall and imposing
荷兰人又人高马大的
You'd just be sightseeing in a hurry
你去那只能走马观花
And you wouldn't have a great experience
也不可能实际体验多好
Why not go to Montpellier
为什么不去蒙彼利埃
Montpellier is truly a paradise on earth
蒙彼利埃才是人间天堂
I also recommend applying to Montpellier University
也建议大家报考蒙皮利埃的大学
And learning French
然后学法语
Going for a master's degree in France
去法国卷研究生
Or becoming a civil servant in Canada
去加拿大卷公务员啊
And thus leading a happy life
从此走向快乐
Life will never be the same
人生再也不行
It's been suppressed
压抑了